Guide to the Albert Hazen Wright Papers, 1820-1960
Hazen Wright, Albert Papers, 1820-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Albert Hazen Wright Papers, 1820-1970
14-26-1382
Albert Hazen, Wright b1879.
32.9 cubic feet; 2 items.
Correspondence, notes, typescripts, genealogies, publications, printed material, transcripts, negatives, slides, photographs, clippings, drawings, census reports, maps, and manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, field notes, lecture notes, study notes, typescripts of articles, genealogies of the Wright family and of Noah Downs, negatives, slides, photographs, clippings, drawings, census reports, maps, New York publications and printed material, transcripts of oral history interviews with Wright, manuscripts of his scientific books, and other material pertaining to his career as a zoologist, university professor, lecturer, and author. Other subjects include the Cornell Natural History Society, the Zoology Department, and the Gamma Alpha Scientific Society; also, study and research notes pertaining to the Okefenokee Swap, Sullivan's Expedition, lizards, snakes, frogs, and other herpetological subjects and issues.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Albert Hazen Wright was born August 15, 1879, in Hilton, NY. His parents were Delos C. Wright and Emily Hazen. He had one younger sister named Mabel. He attended Hilton High School, in Hilton, NY, Brockport Normal School and eventually Cornell University. It was at Cornell where he met Anna Maria Allen whom he married on June 25, 1910. Wright was a Cornell University professor and herpetologist.* He earned his PhD in vertebrate zoology in 1908. He and his wife were interested in the study of amphibians. In 1949, they co-authored the books Handbook of Snakes of the United States and Canada and Handbook of Frogs and Toads of the United States and Canada. The book Life-Histories of the Frogs of Okefinokee Swamp, Georgia: North American Salientia (Anura) No. 2 was written by Albert Hazen Wright and J. Whitfield Gibbons. The Cornell University's herpetology collection is now one of the largest of its kind in the nation. "The major strengths of the collection, amphibians from the southeastern United States and both reptiles and amphibians from the Northeast, reflects the intensive collection by the Wrights. Much of the material collected by the Wrights in New York and Georgia is not duplicated elsewhere."
Between 1921-22, A.H. Wright worked and studied in a part of Georgia known as the Okefenokee Swamp. He befriended Frances Harper who did extensive research on the culture and live of people who lived in the Okefenokee Swamp (See this website http://sherpaguides.com/georgia/okefenokee_swamp/sidebars/francis_harper.html for information on the Francis Harper Papers, which are housed in the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (#3638)). In 1945, the book Our Georgia-Florida Frontier: The Okefenokee Swamp, its History and Cartography... was written by A.H. Wright. He also authored of "Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell VIII" as well as numerous other histories on various aspects of Cornell University. He also spent a lot of time on genealogical research related to the Wright family.
Wright was an honorary member of the International Ornithological Congress. And in 1959, he was elected the 2nd vice president of the Dewitt Historical Society. After years of research and writing, he died in Ithaca, NY in July of 1970, at the age of eighty-one.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, field notes, lecture notes, study notes, typescripts of articles, genealogies of the Wright family and of Noah Downs, negatives, slides, photographs, clippings, drawings, census reports, maps, Cornell University and Ithaca, New York publications and printed material, transcripts of oral history interviews with Wright, manuscripts of his scientific books, and other material pertaining to his career as a zoologist, university professor, lecturer, and author. Other subjects include the Cornell University Natural History Society, the Zoology Department, and the Gamma Alpha Scientific Society; also, study and research notes pertaining to the Okefenokee Swap, Sullivan's Expedition in New York State, lizards, snakes, frogs, and other herpetological subjects and issues.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wright, Albert Hazen,b1879.; Downs, Noah.; Wright family.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Zoology.; Cornell University. Natural History Society.; Gamma Alpha Scientific Society.
Subjects:
Herpetology--Study and teaching.; Zoology--Study and teaching.; Lizards.; Snakes.; Frogs.; Sullivan's Indian Campaign, 1779.; College teachers.
Places:
Okefenokee Swamp.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Genealogy.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Maps.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
RELATED MATERIAL
See also the Burt Green Wilder papers, #14-26-95, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA00095
See also the Department of Zoology Records, #14-26-966, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA00966
See the Frances Harper collection at the University of Chapel Hill, #3638 for more information on the Okefenokee Swamp. in this way.
SERIES LIST
Series I: Biographical Information
Boxes: 1-5
Series II: Personal Correspondence
Boxes 6-8
Series III: Business Correspondence
Boxes 8-14
Series IV: Genealogical Material
Boxes: Boxes 14-16, 63-65
Subseries A: Poll Election Lists
Box 16
Series V: Writings and Miscellaneous Papers
Boxes: Box 46-52, 57, 58, 61, 62, 64, 64
Series VI: Snake Stories and Research
Boxes: Boxes 17-19, 58-61
Series VII: Frog Research
Boxes: 20-22, 53-57
Series VIII: Research Notes
Subseries A: General
Boxes: 19, 23-24
Subseries B: New York State History
Boxes: 5 and 24
Subseries C: Irises
Boxes: 19, 20, 23, 65
Subseries D: Field notebooks
Boxes: 24-26
Series IX: Lizard Research
Boxes: 25 and 27-28
Series X: Okefenokee Swamp
Boxes: 21 and 28-30, 56
Subseries A: Correspondence
Box: 30
Series XI: Cornell University Material
Boxes: 30, 42, 61, 62
Subseries A: Oral Histories
Boxes: 30-31
Subseries B: Department of Neurology and Vertebrate Zoology
Box: 31
Subseries C: Teaching Material
Boxes: 31-32
Subseries D: Correspondence
Box: 32
Subseries E: Albert Hazen and Anna Allen Wright's School Days
Boxes: 32-33 and 35
Subseries F: National Research Council
Box: 23
Subseries G: Histories of Cornell University
Boxes: 33-34
Series XII: Published Material
Boxes: 5, 16, 34, and 46
Series XIII: Photographs, Photo Albums, and Scrapbooks
Boxes: 4, 37-40, 43, and 46, 62
Subseries A: Glass Plate Negatives
Boxes: Boxes: 39-41, 43-45
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - A.H. Wright's Diary and Alumni Banquet Program from Hilton High School (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A.H. Wright's Autograph and Check Book, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.H. Wright's Manual of Geography (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brockport Normal School-memorabilia and yearbook, 1897-99 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs and recommendations from Cornell University, 1901-04 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journal (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Delos C. Wright and Mabel Wright), 1901-39 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Delos C. and Emily Wright's Christmas Cards, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Delos C. Wright's Patent, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Delos C. Wright's Patent Bracket for Scaffold, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Eyeglasses (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pins and Buttons (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Delos C. Wright's Ledgers (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Delos C. Wright's Ledgers (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Delos C. Wright's Diaries, 1879-1911 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Delos C. Wright's Diary and Memorandum Books (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Jane Hazen's Diaries, 1883-1904 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Tax Roll Journal, 1904-05 (Box 1)
  - Tax Roll Journal, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Elizabeth Hazen Wright's Diary and Ledger Books (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - R. Hazen's Diary and Miscellaneous Ledger Books (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Bills and Papers of Delos C. Wright, 1910-17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Anna Allen's Cornelliana scrapbook (Box 2)
  - Anna Allen's Cornelliana scrapbook (Box 2)
  - Anna Allen's 1909 Stunt Book (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A. W and A.A.Wright's wedding invitation (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Anna A. Wrights' Photo Album from the Cornell Biological Expedition, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Anna A. Wright's Scrapbook of Cornell University Memorabilia (Box 2)
  - Anna Wright's Scrapbook, 1910-14 (Box 3)
  - Anna Allen's Victorian scrapbook (Box 4)
  - A.H. Wright's registration and billing information (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Banking records, 1914-15 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Anna A. Wright's song books (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Address book (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Series II: Personal Correspondence
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, 1906-07 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, May-June, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, June-July, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, July, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, July-Aug., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Aug., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Aug., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Sept., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Sept., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Dec., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Jan., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Apr.-June, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, June-July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - A.A. Wright to A.H. Wright, July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Aug., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Aug., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Sept., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, July-Aug., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Nov., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Dec., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Jan., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Jan., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Jan., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Feb.-March., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Mar.-May, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, June, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, Apr.-May, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, May-June, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - A.H. Wright to A. Allen, June-July, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, July, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, June-Aug., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Aug.-Sept., 1908 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, 1908-12 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Jan.-June, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, June-July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, July, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Aug., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Aug.-Sept., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Sept., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Sept., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Oct., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Oct., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Nov., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Nov.-Dec., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Dec., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Nov., 1909-Jan., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Jan., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Jan.-Feb., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Feb.-May, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Mar.-Apr., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Apr., 1910 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - A. Allen to A.H. Wright, Dec., 1909-May, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - A.A. Wright to A.H. Wright, 1910-11 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - A.H. Wright to A.A. Wright, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - A.A. Wright to A.H. Wright, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - A.A. Wright to A.H. Wright, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - A.A. Wright to A.H. Wright (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous-A. Allen, 1906-09 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous-A.A. Wright, 1909-10 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous-A.A. Wright, 1910-34 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous-A.A. Wright, 1918-34 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - D.W. Allen to A. Allen, 1908-09 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Allen and Wright Families, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Wright Family, 1903-05 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Wright Family, 1904-06 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Wright Family, 1905-08 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Wright Family, 1906-09 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Wright Family, 1907-10 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Wright Family, 1907-10 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Wright Family, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Wright Family, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Wright Family, 1919-41 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - A.H. and A.A. Wright's Christmas Cards, 1940's (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - A.H. and A.A. Wright's Christmas Cards, 1950-59 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - A.H. and A.A. Wright's Christmas Cards, 1960-66 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Letterbook-miscellaneous, 1913-66 (Box 7)
  - Letterbook-Greetings to Albert Hazen Wright, 1946-47 (Box 7)
  - Letterbook-Retirement Replies to Party Treasure Letters, 1947-63 (Box 7)
  - A.H. Wright to D.C. Wright, 1896-1900 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Family, 1963-66 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Family, 1966-70 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Family, 1966-70 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Invitations and Friendly Greetings, 1962-69 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Invitations and Friendly Greetings, 1966-69 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Invitations and Friendly Greetings, 1965-66 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Birthday Greetings, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Invitations and Friendly Greetings, 1968-70 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Invitations (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Wedding invitations and birth announcements (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Letterbook-Christmas/Birthday-Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Letterbook-Anna A. Wright's Christmas Versus (Box 8)
  - Letterbook-Christmas (Vol. I), 1965 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook-Christmas (Vol. II), 1965 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook-Christmas, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook-Christmas, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook-Birthday Party, 1966 (Box 8)
- Series III. Business Correspondence
  - A, 1906-11 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A, 1918-29 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - A, 1930-35 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A, 1935-40 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - A, 1940-41 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - A, 1943-47 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - A, 1948-59 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - A, 1960-65 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Academy of Zoology-Agra, India, 1955-61 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Naturalist and American Ornithologist's Union, 1891-1933 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Allen, Arthur A., 1909-24 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - American Microscopical Society and American Museum of Natural History, 1910-22 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - American Philosophical Society and American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists, 1910-35 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Association, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - American Antiquarian Society & American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1918-32 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - American Society of Mammalogists and American Society of Zoologists, 1925-28 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - American Geographical Society, 1928-29 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Alee, W.C., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Faculty Reports, 1937-42 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Adelman, H.B., 1944-47 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - B, 1905-24 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - B, 1925-29 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - B, 1930-35 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - B, 1936-39 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - B, 1940-41 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - B, 1945-49 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - B, 1950-66 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Bailey, Liberty Hyde, 1916-46 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - George Banta Publishing Co., 1943-47 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Bates, Eleanor, 1937-38 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Bishop, Alice, 1966-69 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Bishop, Sherman C., 1916-28 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Bishop, Sherman C., 1916-32 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Bishop, Sherman C., 1922-48 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Blanchard, Frank N, 1909-34 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Bo, 1909-35 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Bradley, J. Chester, 1910-17 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Bu, 1912-44 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Bureau of Fisheries, 1910-30 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - C, 1891-1919 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - C, 1920-23 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - C, 1925-30 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - C, 1931-35 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - C, 1936-39 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - C, 1940-42 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - C, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - C, 1944-45 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - C, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - C, 1947-49 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - C, 1950-59 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - C, 1960-66 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - C, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Comstock, Anna, 1907-14 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Connt, Roger, 1930-42 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - D, 1907-19 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - D, 1920-29 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - D, 1930-35 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - D, 1935-40 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - D, 1940-43 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - D, 1944-47 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - D, 1950-59 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - D, 1960-65 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dunham, Ann, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Day, Edmund, 1940-46 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - E, 1905-10 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - E, 1918-31 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - E, 1932-40 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - E, 1943-46 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - E, 1959-64 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ecological Society of America, 1935-37 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ecological Society of America, 1936-44 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - F, 1907-19 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - F, 1909-29 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - F, 1930-35 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - F, 1936-39 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - F, 1940-49 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - F, 1950-59 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - F, 1960-65 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Farrand, Livingston, 1923-34 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1910-12 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Funkhouser, W.D., 1912-36 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Florida Ship Canal, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Florida Ship Canal, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Florida Ship Canal, 1936-37 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Florida Ship Canal Requests, 1944-48 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - G, 1906-19 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - G, 1920-29 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - G, 1930-36 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - G, 1937-39 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - G, 1940-43 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - G, 1944-45 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - G, 1946-49 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - G, 1950-59 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - G, 1960-65 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Gage, Simon Henry, 188-1932 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Gloyd, Howard K., 1928-34 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Griscom, Ludlow, 1916-17 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Graduate School Faculty, 1938-42 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - H, 1904-09 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - H, 1910-19 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - H, 1920-29 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - H, 1930-35 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - H, 1936-39 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - H, 1940-43 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - H, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - H, 1945-46 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - 1947-49 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - H, 1950-54 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - H, 1955-59 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - H, 1960-66 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Happ, George B., 1920-35 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Hasbrouck, Henry Crane, 1908-19 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Harper, Francis, 1912-24 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - I, 1910-65 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - J, 1910-33 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - J, 1934-41 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - J, 1942-49 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - J, 1952-66 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jopson, H.G.M., 1927-36 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - K, 1911-19 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - K, 1909-25 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - K, 1926-29 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - K, 1930-34 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - K, 1935-37 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - K, 1938-40 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - K, 1941-44 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - K, 1945-47 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - K, 1948-50 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - K, 1951-55 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - K, 1956-59 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - K, 1960-65 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Kibbe, Alice, 1920-53 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Kirn, Albert J., 1933 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Klauber, L.M., 1928 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Klauber, L.M., 1928-30 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - L, 1907-19 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - L, 1920-29 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - L, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - L, 1936-39 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - L, 1940-45 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - L, 1946-49 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - L, 1950-55 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - L, 1956-59 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - L, 1960-65 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Liu, Charles C., 1932-35 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Lloyd, John T., 1920-35 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Library and Book Requests- Cornell University, 1922-33 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1934-38 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1938-39 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1939-43 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Library- Cornell University, 1943-47 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Agricultural Library-Cornell University, 1939-43 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Agricultural Library-Cornell University, 1941-47 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Agricultural Library-Cornell University, 1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Library Associates-Cornell University, 1943-48 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Library Extension Collection-Cornell University, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Library Extension Collection-Cornell University, 1944-46 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - M, 1906-19 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - M, 1920-25 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - M, 1925-29 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - M, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - M, 1936-39 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - M, 1940-44 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - M, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - M, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - M, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - M, 1930-35 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Malott, Dean W., 1952-60 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Mann, A.R., 1918-33 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - McAtee, W.L., 1920-44 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Moesel, Julia, 1912-14 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Moore, Emmeline, 1926-41 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mulaik, Stanley, 1931-37 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Munz, Philip J., 1917-35 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Murray, Leo T., 1927-38 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Museum Needs (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - N, 1910-25 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - N, 1926-36 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - N, 1937-43 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - N, 1943-44 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - N, 1944-46 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - N, 1947-65 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Needham, J.G., 1915-65 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Netting, Graham, 1928-33 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Noble, G.K., 1922-26 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - National Research Council, 1934-36 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - National Research Council, 1935-37 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - National Research Council, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - National Research Council, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - National Research Council, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - National Research Council, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - National Research Council, 1937-38 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - National Research Council, 1936-41 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - National Research Council, 1937-41 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - National Research Council-Committee on Conservation, 1936-41 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - National Research Council-Committee on Conservation, 1936-41 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - National Research Council-Wildlife, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - National Research Council-Wildlife, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1915-37 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - National Association of Audubon Societies, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Newsletter (Zoology), 1945 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - N.Y.A. Student Aid, 1938-43 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - O, 1910-29 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - O, 1930-39 (Box 12, Folder 35)